toronto2015.org 2014-03-27

# Privacy Policy | Toronto 2015 Pan Am / Parapan American Games

## Use and Discolsure of Personal Information 

**_Use of Personal Information:_**

TO2015™ will use the personal information we collect to:

  * provide stakeholders with news about the Games;
  * manage our business;
  * sell merchandise and tickets;
  * comply with regulatory and industry requirements;
  * create and maintain our vendor accounts
  * communicate with our stakeholders.

We may also use information about stakeholder interests and preferences, as well as feedback we receive from surveys, to improve our delivery of the Games. TO2015™ makes all reasonable efforts to ensure that information is used responsibly and only for its intended purposes. 

We may provide your personal information to any third-party service provider that administers any Games facility, service and/or promotion operated via our website, [TORONTO 2015.org](http://toronto2015.org/) (“the Site”) on our behalf. Your personal information will be provided to such third-party service providers only to enable its proper administration that Games facility, service or promotion.  We may use your personal information to operate the features of the Site and to allow you, when you choose to do so, to participate in features available only to registered users or interactive features of the Site.

When you sign up to take part in a program or initiative that we may operate from time to time, or to receive online and/or email communications (e.g. our supporters’ or partners’ newsletters or business e-alerts) or text communications (e.g. communications enabled via the Site between us and users of mobile telephones or other portable devices), we may use the information that you provide to maintain appropriate databases and otherwise to operate and facilitate such programs, networks and communications.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside Canada for processing by TO2015™ staff operating outside Canada and/or third-party service providers contracted by us. If you submit personal information, you specifically consent by doing so to such transfer, storing or processing. We will endeavor to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Access to personal information shall be restricted to those individuals or agents who require access to personal information in order to perform their duties and where access is necessary and proper for the administration of the program. 

**_Disclosure of Personal Information:_**

_To whom we disclose your personal information:_ Depending on the nature of the information our stakeholders require, we may disclose personal information to our federal, provincial, municipal funding partners, sponsors, financial institutions, credit reporting agencies and third-party service providers such as data processing and marketing companies.

We will disclose your personal information if we reasonably believe that we are required to do so by law, regulation, court order or any competent governmental, statutory or public authority or to protect our rights and property or the rights and property of our stakeholders. We may also co-operate with law-enforcement agencies in any official investigation, and we may disclose your private information to such agencies in doing so.

_When we will get your consent:_ We will request your express consent to the use and disclosure of your personal information for specific types of transactions on the application or other forms used in connection with those transactions. Where it is reasonable to imply your consent to the use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Policy (e.g., in connection with a background check following an application for accreditation), we may do so. Where it is reasonable, we may also imply your ongoing consent to the continued use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Policy where we make additional requests for information. We will obtain your express consent before using or disclosing your personal information for any purposes not identified in this Policy.

The use and disclosure of personal information of specific stakeholders is described below:

_**Employees and Contractors**_

TO2015™ collects and uses its employees’ and contractors’ information with the main focus of supporting its workforce. TO2015™ may from time to time operate online job application systems. We may also collect personal information for the purpose of a job application in hard copy. If you submit such an application, we may process the information provided by you for the purpose of considering the application. If your application is not accepted at that time, we may retain and store your personal information in a recruitment database for the purpose of future recruitment.

If you have applied for a paid position with TO2015™, we will disclose your personal information to agencies conducting security, background and credit checks on our behalf.

In the event your application is accepted and you become an employee or contractor of TO2015™, your personal information will processed for payroll and benefits purposes. Your personal information may be provided to third-party payroll and employee benefits providers in order to manage TO2015’s payroll and benefits programs. Your personal information will also be shared with the federal and provincial governments for the purpose of administering the income tax regime in compliance with the Income Tax Act. 

TO2015™ will disclose personal information related to your employment, should such disclosure be required by law. 

_**Sponsors**_

Sponsorship is critical to the promotion, financing and staging of the Games. TO2015’s sponsorship initiative requires the collection of personal information from all sponsors and potential sponsors. A sponsor’s personal information may collected and compiled into a contact list containing TO2015™ sponsors and partners (“ **Contact List** ”).

The Contact List will be shared with each sponsor and partner for the purpose of fostering current, and promoting future, business opportunities. The Contact List will also be shared will our federal and provincial government funding partners. TO2015™ will contact you in order to obtain your consent if we receive a request to disclose your personal information to one of our municipal partners.

The personal information of TO2015™ sponsors and partners will not be disclosed to any third parties aside from those named above, unless expressly consent to by the sponsor or partner.

_**Athletes**_

TO2015™ will collect personal information of all athletes, coaches and athletic staff participating in the Games. Personal information collected from athletes, coaches and athletic staff may be processed for the purpose of, among other things, security and accreditation. Personal information of athletes may also be used and disclosed in various ways in order to host, promote and stage the Games. The purposes of such disclosure include, but are not limited to, broadcasting events, marketing and promotions. The activities of athletes may be photographed, recorded, distributed and used by TO2015™ as part of its official, promotional or educational material and may be used in any medium or form or with any support and without any compensation. 

Medical data relating to participating athletes may be collected in association with the Games; the use and disclosure of such information is addressed in a separate privacy policy. 

_**Volunteers**_

TO2015™ may from time to time operate online volunteer application systems. We may also collect personal information for the purpose of a volunteer application in hard copy. If you submit such an application, your personal information will be collected and processed by our third-party application and digital interview service providers for the limited purpose of considering your application.

If you have applied for a volunteer position with TO2015™, we will disclose your personal information to agencies conducting security and background checks on our behalf.

The TO2015™ volunteer program seeks to create a lasting legacy of trained, competent and experienced volunteers that will benefit Toronto, the Greater Golden Horseshoe region and Ontario. In the event your application is accepted and you become a Games volunteer, your personal information may be shared with external organizations including, but not limited to, municipal and provincial government partners for use during the Games and for the purpose of informing you of future opportunities in the region, or to support government oversight of the Games. If you indicate intent to apply for benefits from the Ontario Student Assistance Program (“OSAP”), your personal information will be disclosed to the provincial government for the purpose of administering future OSAP benefits.

Some volunteers will have the opportunity to operate official TO2015™ vehicles during the Games. The personal information of these individuals may be provided to the Ontario Ministry of Transportation in accordance with TO2015™ fleet program. 

The activities of TO2015™ volunteers may be photographed, distributed and used by TO2015 as part of its official, promotional or educational material and may be used in any medium or form or with any support and without any compensation. Your image, likeness, voice or performance (or all of these) may be made available to TO2015™ whether such images and recordings have been or will be: (a) made or taken by any TO2015™employee or agent; or b) made or taken by me or any other person and submitted by me or another person on my behalf to TO2015™ or a TO2015™ representative.

TO2015™ will operate its call centre from facilities provided by the Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce (CIBC). Personal information provided by volunteers may be disclosed to CIBC for the purposes of administering the call centre.

**_Vendors and Suppliers_**

TO2015™ has and will continue to contract with corporations and/or individuals as vendors and suppliers of products and services critical to the success of the Games. Personal information of vendors and suppliers is collected through the public procurement process.

Upon a vendor or supplier’s consent, TO2015™ may disclose vendor or supplier information to CIBC for Business Leads who have signed up through the TO2015™ website. This information includes email, phone number, company name, company address, contact name and job title (“Contact Information”). This personal information may be used for the purpose of informing you of potential future business opportunities. In connection with the RFP process, TO2015™ will disclose RFP award winner Contact Information to CIBC, for the same reason stated above. Consent will have already been provided by the vendor or supplier upon submission of the RFP.

TO2015™ is committed to the confidential and sensitive nature of procurement agreements, and for that reason, does not make any procurement agreements public, unless compelled to by law. Procurement agreements may be shared with our federal and provincial government partners in order to properly plan, finance and stage the Games. All procurement agreements are kept secure and private and are accessible only to the TO2015™ Procurement and TO2015™ Legal Departments. Similarly, TO2015™ does not make any of the RFP proposal submissions public. Only the TO2015 Evaluation Committee and TO2015™ Procurement Department can view these documents, including pricing. From time to time, third-party consultants participate on evaluation committees. In these circumstances, the third-party consultant is subject to a confidentiality agreement.

_**Contests**_

In order to promote the Games, TO2015™ may from time to time run promotional contests. Such contests may be operated through an online entry or registration system. If you submit a completed contest registration or entry form, we may process the information provided by you for the purpose of administering the contest. 

With your prior consent, your information may be used by TO2015™ to send you our electronic newsletters or other such publications and information relating to other TO2015™ promotions, contests, events or Games programs. 

From time to time, TO2015™ may run co-sponsored promotional contests. If you submit a completed contest registration form to one of TO2015™ co-sponsored contest, we may disclose information provided by you to our co-sponsor.

The activities of TO2015™ contest entrants may be photographed, distributed and used by TO2015™ as part of its official, promotional or educational material and may be used in any medium or form or with any support and without any compensation. Your image, likeness, voice or performance (or all of these) may be made available to TO2015™ whether such images and recordings have been or will be: (a) made or taken by any TO2015™ employee or agent; or b) made or taken by me or any other person and submitted by me or another person on my behalf to TO2015™ or a TO2015™ representative.

**_Social Media_**

When you sign up to follow or communicate with social media accounts that we may operate from time to time, and/or to receive communications from TO2015™ through these social media outlets, we may use the information that you provide to maintain, operate and facilitate such programs, networks and communications. Personal information that you provide to TO2015™ via social media account(s) is collected to capture conversations (e.g. questions and answers, comments, “likes”, retweets) between you and TO2015™. It may be used to respond to inquiries, contact you about giveaways or for statistical, evaluation and reporting purposes. This information will not be “mined” or stored by TO2015™; however, your personal information may be collected, used and disclosed by the social media account administrator, independent of TO2015™. Before engaging or communicating with TO2015™, we strongly recommend that you review and understand the privacy policy, settings and information sharing functions of the social media website.

TO2015’s use of social media serves as an extension of its presence on the web. Social media account(s) are public and are not hosted on TO2015™ servers. If you choose to interact with us via social media, you should read the privacy policies of these third-party service providers and those of any applications you use to access them. TO2015™ uses Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, YouTube and LinkedIn.

**_Torch Relay_**

The Pan Am / Parapan Am Torch Relay will engage the public and showcase our partners, sponsors and participating municipalities. We may collect personal information of Torch Relay participants and may process such information for the purpose of planning, promoting and staging the Torch Relay.

TO2015™ may from time to time operate online Torch Relay application systems. If you submit such an application, your personal information will be collected and processed by our third-party application service providers for the limited purpose of considering your application.

If you have applied for a Torch Relay position with TO2015™, we may disclose your personal information to agencies conducting security and background checks on our behalf.

The TO2015™ Torch Relay is a sponsored event. TO2015™ may disclose information provided by you to our sponsors. 

Some Torch Relay volunteers will have the opportunity to operate official TO2015™ vehicles during the Games. The personal information of these individuals may be provided to the Ontario Ministry of Transportation in accordance with TO2015™ fleet program. 

The activities of Torch Relay volunteers may be photographed, distributed and used by TO2015™ as part of its official, promotional or educational material and may be used in any medium or form or with any support and without any compensation. Your image, likeness, voice or performance (or all of these) may be made available to TO2015™ whether such images and recordings have been or will be: (a) made or taken by any TO2015™ employee or agent; or b) made or taken by me or any other person and submitted by me or another person on my behalf to TO2015™ or a TO2015™ representative.
